<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>aetna &#124; health section &#187; Syndicate – Individuals &amp; Families</title>
	<atom:link href="http://wpaetna.lampdev.cmgrp.com/tag/syndicate-individuals-families/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://wpaetna.lampdev.cmgrp.com</link>
	<description>The Health Section</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 20:28:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.9-RC2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>New health care model to cut costs, improve care</title>
		<link>http://wpaetna.lampdev.cmgrp.com/new-health-care-model-to-cut-costs-improve-care-2/</link>
		<comments>http://wpaetna.lampdev.cmgrp.com/new-health-care-model-to-cut-costs-improve-care-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 20:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dante Fattoruso]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accountable care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accountable care organizations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accountable care solutions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Syndicate – Individuals & Families]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.aetna.com/?p=342</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Can &#8220;accountable care organizations&#8221; fix the broken health care system? Early results look promising. A middle-aged man collapses at work due to high blood sugar level. He ends up in the Intensive Care Unit. A woman in her sixties with &#8230; <a href="http://wpaetna.lampdev.cmgrp.com/new-health-care-model-to-cut-costs-improve-care-2/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Can &#8220;accountable care organizations&#8221; fix the broken health care system? Early results look promising.</h2>
<p>A middle-aged man collapses at work due to high blood sugar level. He ends up in the Intensive Care Unit. A woman in her sixties with congestive heart failure stops taking her medication after she leaves the hospital because of exhaustion. She lands right back in the hospital.</p>
<p>These are common scenarios in the American health care system. But if these people were closely monitored and their doctors had access to their full medical histories, could we prevent patients like from going to the hospital in the first place?</p>
<p>The architects behind accountable care organizations (ACOs) say yes.</p>
<p>An ACO is a group of health care professionals, centers and insurers that work together to care for patients. The ACO can include hospitals and hospital systems, primary care doctors and specialists, and a health insurance company. The goal is to improve patient care and reduce the overall costs of health care.</p>
<p>&#8220;Accountable care puts patients at the center of what we do,&#8221; Becky Cook, chief financial officer of the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6Pk5vZ30jms&amp;list=PL0ovlWLRVVGvITXJsHtqvQS9QtmZsJuis" target="_blank">Memorial Hermann Physician Network</a>, said. &#8220;Part of it is about engaging people to make decisions about their health.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote class="full-width"><p>“In the first year in the Pioneer ACO program, Banner Health Network delivered more than $13 million in shared savings.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Right now, about 14 percent of the population in the United States is served by an ACO, according to a <a href="http://www.oliverwyman.com/content/dam/oliver-wyman/global/en/files/archive/2012/ACO_press_release(2).pdf" target="_blank">study</a> by the consulting firm Oliver Wyman. This includes about four million Medicare patients, as reported by the <a href="https://www.cms.gov/Newsroom/MediaReleaseDatabase/Press-Releases/2013-Press-Releases-Items/2013-07-16.html" target="_blank">Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services</a> (CMS).</p>
<p>In 2010, the CMS launched several ACO pilot programs as part of the Affordable Care Act. The goal was to keep costs down by reducing <a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2014/01/30/half-of-medicare-acos-achieve-savings/5054433/" target="_blank">hospitalizations</a>. With the ACO team working together, the group tries to avoid duplicate tests, negative drug interactions and treatment errors.</p>
<aside class="offset left blue"><a href="http://www.aetnaacs.com/what-makes-accountable-care-solutions-aetna-different" target="_blank">Aetna was cited as the most “transformational” payer, according to providers.<br />
<span class="cta">Read More&#8221;</span>  </a></aside>
<p>&#8220;We use technology to connect patients with our care coordination team,&#8221; Dr. T. K. Desai, chief medical officer of PrimeCare Southern California, said. This means patient information must be available electronically and at all sites of the system.</p>
<p>In January 2014, the CMS <a href="http://www.hhs.gov/news/press/2014pres/01/20140130a.html" target="_blank">released results</a> from several ACO pilot programs, demonstrating over $380 million in total savings. In one of these pilots—the Pioneer ACOs program—only 28 percent of the participating organizations showed decreased Medicare spending. The program overall, however, still generated nearly $147 million in savings over the first year while providing high-quality care.</p>
<p>One of the success stories in the Pioneer ACO program was <a href="http://www.bannerhealth.com/" target="_blank">Banner Health Network</a>. In 2011, Aetna began working with the Banner Health Network to develop its own accountable care business model. This collaboration includes an agreement in which Aetna and Banner Health share financial risks, allowing Banner to focus on quality, efficiency and patient satisfaction.</p>
<p>In the first year in the Pioneer ACO program, Banner Health Network delivered more than <a href="http://www.bannerhealth.com/About+Us/News+Center/Press+Releases/Press+Archive/2013/BHN+delivers+quality+care+at+a+lower+cost+in+the+Medicare+Pioneer+models+first+year.htm" target="_blank">$13 million in shared savings</a>. In addition, the organization also reduced hospital admissions and readmissions as well as the average length of stay in a hospital.</p>
<p>&#8220;Through our experience, we believe the value-based Pioneer ACO model has merit, and that it has the potential to diminish the predominance of fee-for-service plans in government and private sectors,&#8221; Chuck Lehn, CEO for Banner Health Network, said in a <a href="http://www.bannerhealth.com/About+Us/News+Center/Press+Releases/Press+Archive/2013/BHN+delivers+quality+care+at+a+lower+cost+in+the+Medicare+Pioneer+models+first+year.htm" target="_blank">statement</a>. &#8220;It is the best solution at this time for creating sustainability for the Medicare program, and could be the basis for historic change in the U.S. health care industry.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wpaetna.lampdev.cmgrp.com/new-health-care-model-to-cut-costs-improve-care-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
