<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>aetna &#124; health section &#187; Syndicate &#8211; Healthcare Professionals</title>
	<atom:link href="http://wpaetna.lampdev.cmgrp.com/tag/syndicate-healthcare-professionals/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://wpaetna.lampdev.cmgrp.com</link>
	<description>The Health Section</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 20:28:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.9-RC2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Prescription medications: new ways to ensure access</title>
		<link>http://wpaetna.lampdev.cmgrp.com/prescription-medications-new-ways-to-ensure-access/</link>
		<comments>http://wpaetna.lampdev.cmgrp.com/prescription-medications-new-ways-to-ensure-access/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 20:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dante Fattoruso]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drug prices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care costs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Syndicate - Healthcare Professionals]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.aetna.com/?p=327</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The high costs of prescription medications are a burden to health care. We must find ways to provide patients affordable access. Over the past year, Gilead’s new hepatitis-c treatment Sovaldi has received significant attention. While shown to be very effective, &#8230; <a href="http://wpaetna.lampdev.cmgrp.com/prescription-medications-new-ways-to-ensure-access/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>The high costs of prescription medications are a burden to health care. We must find ways to provide patients affordable access.</h2>
<p>Over the past year, Gilead’s new hepatitis-c treatment Sovaldi has received significant attention. While shown to be very effective, the treatment has been tagged as a symbol for how the prices of complex pharmaceuticals are reaching dizzying heights. It is one of the most expensive drugs to ever hit the market at $1,000 a pill.</p>
<p>At Aetna, we know it is important for patients to have access to the best treatments possible, and we have several initiatives to lower the cost barriers for our members. But we know that controlling the costs of prescriptions drugs is not something we can do alone.</p>
<p>When not predicted accurately, prescription drug costs can create a burden on health plans and affect the health care system as a whole. Even when costs are accurately predicted and included in premiums, drug costs can still be a driver of overall uptrend in health care costs.</p>
<p>Many medication costs have increased at a rate of 15 percent every year, but health care companies cannot increase premiums by that much without triggering a federal audit. If this trend continues, drug companies may price themselves out of the market in a few years.</p>
<p>Pharmaceutical drug costs are <a href="http://www.cms.gov/Research-Statistics-Data-and-Systems/Statistics-Trends-and-Reports/NationalHealthExpendData/downloads/proj2012.pdf" target="_blank">expected to rise</a> each year through 2022. Meanwhile, U.S. pharmaceutical consumption continues to soar. The average American spends $1,000 a year on pharmaceuticals. That’s 40 percent higher than second-most Canada, according to <a href="http://www.oecd.org/unitedstates/49084355.pdf" target="_blank">data</a> from the Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development.</p>
<p>As a health insurer, we can only take some indirect measures to drive down costs. We can help make sure drugs are prescribed and managed more carefully to avoid misuse.</p>
<blockquote class="full-width"><p>“The average American spends $1,000 a year on pharmaceuticals, 40% higher than second-most Canada”</p></blockquote>
<p>Raising consumer awareness could reduce reliance on certain treatments. For example, maybe the need for expensive cancer drugs could be cut by helping smokers quit.</p>
<p>However, if we are seriously concerned about the amount of U.S. gross domestic product that goes into health care, long-term solutions must be developed to reduce the cost of pharmaceuticals.</p>
<aside class="offset right blue"><a href="http://www.aetna.com/faqs-health-insurance/pharmacy-coverage-costs-faqs.html" target="_blank">Learn more about our prescription drug coverage and costs. </a></aside>
<p>One possibility to control prescription drug costs is more transparency in the way drug development is financed. Removing speculation and increasing certainty in final approval will help to lower development costs.</p>
<p>As part of the 2010 health reform law, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Physician_Payments_Sunshine_Act" target="_blank">The Physician Payment Sunshine Act</a> will require pharmaceutical and medical device companies to publicly report their payments to physicians who publicly endorse their products, starting in September 2014. Already, many U.S pharmaceutical companies have begun cutting payments to physician public speakers, according to <a href="http://www.propublica.org/article/as-full-disclosure-nears-doctors-pay-for-drug-talks-plummets" target="_blank">a new study from ProPublica</a>.</p>
<p>In addition, we need to improve efficiency and transparency in the early stages of drug development to reduce the number of failures in late phase testing. Currently, the substantial number of failures in the later stages of development is extremely costly.</p>
<p>We need to test potential treatments earlier and on more people to understand if a particular drug is effective or not. The question is, can we and the Food and Drug Administration get more creative around studies to make some earlier decisions about the chances a particular drug has to make it.</p>
<p>The current trend of increasing prescription drug costs is not sustainable for our health care system. Health care companies must continue to work with pharmaceutical companies, policymakers and patients to provide access to effective and affordable treatments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wpaetna.lampdev.cmgrp.com/prescription-medications-new-ways-to-ensure-access/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
