<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>aetna &#124; health section &#187; Syndicate – Employers &amp; Organizations</title>
	<atom:link href="http://wpaetna.lampdev.cmgrp.com/tag/syndicate-employers-organizations/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://wpaetna.lampdev.cmgrp.com</link>
	<description>The Health Section</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 20:28:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.9-RC2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Controlling health costs: the carrot or the stick?</title>
		<link>http://wpaetna.lampdev.cmgrp.com/controlling-health-costs-the-carrot-or-the-stick/</link>
		<comments>http://wpaetna.lampdev.cmgrp.com/controlling-health-costs-the-carrot-or-the-stick/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 20:23:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dante Fattoruso]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care costs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Syndicate – Employers & Organizations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wellness incentives]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.aetna.com/?p=313</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The assumption is that incentives are the best way to get people to take healthy actions, but could penalties work better? An MRI can cost $300 or $1200. If you have health insurance, you are probably responsible for paying a &#8230; <a href="http://wpaetna.lampdev.cmgrp.com/controlling-health-costs-the-carrot-or-the-stick/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>The assumption is that incentives are the best way to get people to take healthy actions, but could penalties work better?</h2>
<p>An MRI can cost $300 or $1200. If you have health insurance, you are probably responsible for paying a percentage of this cost. Let’s say 20%. So would you rather write a check for $60 or $240?</p>
<p>Today, people are more responsible for their health care decisions. And employers encourage this. It’s in their best interest to help employees understand how health plans work.</p>
<p>“Companies have to control spending,” said Mary Mooney, senior marketing manager at health management and analytics company ActiveHealth Management. One way to control spending is to give people tools so they can see what services cost. Armed with that information, they can decide how to spend their money.</p>
<p>Another way to promote engagement is to use “carrots and sticks” to direct behaviors.</p>
<p>“Many companies have spent the last few years building a culture of health,” Mooney said. “To foster that, businesses have to get people to be active participants in their health.”</p>
<p>Employers have experimented with “carrots” such as cash, gift cards and deposits into health savings accounts.</p>
<p>In a <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s13142-013-0211-6" target="_blank">study</a> published in <i>Translational Behavioral Medicine </i>in 2013, researchers found that when employees were given the choice of paying higher health insurance premiums or meeting a fitness goal, most chose exercise. In the end, nearly 97 percent of those who enrolled in one of the fitness programs offered in the study met their fitness goals.</p>
<aside class="offset right blue"><a href="http://www.aetna.com/insurance-producer/health-wellness/wellness-programs.html " target="_blank">Our suite of more 70 wellness programs spans the continuum of care.</a></aside>
<p>&#8220;There are ethical debates around the idea of forcing someone to be personally responsible for health care costs related to not exercising, but we expect to see more of these approaches to financially motivate healthier behaviors,&#8221; study author Caroline R. Richardson, MD, assistant professor in the University of Michigan Department of Family Medicine, said in a <a href="https://www.uofmhealth.org/news/archive/201305/5000-steps-day-avoid-higher-health-insurance-costs-when" target="_blank">statement</a>.</p>
<p>Most incentives are simple. Like $50 if you take a health risk assessment. Or the employer makes a contribution to the employee’s health savings account for joining a wellness class. Negative reinforcement, or “sticks,” include actions such as increases in plan premiums and canceled reimbursements.</p>
<p>The long-held assumption is that incentives are the best way to get people to take healthy actions.</p>
<p>But data from a 2014 study suggest that “carrots” do not work alone. The study looked at 1.9 million ActiveHealth members over a 5-year period.</p>
<p>Researchers found that while incentives lead to a modest boost in engagement with disease management programs, penalties did much better. Consumers were 13 times more likely to be active in managing their disease when failing to do so could cost them directly.</p>
<p>However, when it came to participating in wellness programs, like lifestyle coaching, researchers saw the opposite trend. “Sticks” lowered performance overall. In this case, incentives increased participation by 3 percent.</p>
<blockquote class="full-width"><p>“Consumers were 13 times more likely to be active in managing their disease when failing to do so could cost them directly.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Why were sticks are more effective in disease management programs rather than wellness programs? Well, wellness programs have a much higher level of engagement to begin with when compared with disease management programs. So making a significant impact is easier when engagement is poor.</p>
<p>In addition, participants in wellness programs are more likely to lead a healthier lifestyle and are intrinsically motivated. Participants in the disease management programs, however, are more likely to make poor health choices and be extrinsically motivated.</p>
<p>“When employers set up incentive programs, they may not be considering all the nuances,” Mooney said. “But the nuances are where the opportunity lies.” And maybe the biggest savings.</p>
<p>In the end, designing an incentive strategy more of an art than a science. There is no one-size-fits-all way to promote health care consumerism. Social interactions, competition and camaraderie seem to significantly influence motivation, willingness to take action, and sustain engagement over the long haul.</p>
<p>Finding the right balance of “carrots” and “sticks” may be key to helping people take greater responsibility for their own health care.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wpaetna.lampdev.cmgrp.com/controlling-health-costs-the-carrot-or-the-stick/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
